Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-dodge5/ GitHub: https://github.com/nicoledodge

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer in the MERN stack, specializing in Javascript and Node. Expertise in developing web pages using HTML5, CSS3, MVC, SASS, Object Oriented Javascript, ES6, JQuery, AJAX, JSON, XML, REACT. Good understanding of Document Object Model (DOM) and DOM Functions. Extensive use of Node environment using NPM, Express, mySQL and MongoDB along with Mongoose.JS to create server side applications. Experience in creating the user validation forms and using the RESTful services for sending the data to the server. Good experience on working with CSS Background, padding, table, Animations, Pseudo classes and Layouts, positioning, border, margin, Pseudo elements and CSS behaviors including the Box model and Flex properties. Graphic design experience in Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom and Adobe Illustrator.

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Austin, TX - Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

SEPTEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

Texas State University, San Marcos, TX - BA in International Relations

AUGUST 2016 - MAY 2020

SKILLS

•	JavaScript	
•	Javascript	

- Git
- HTML/CSS
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- Materialize

- API design knowledge
- JSON
- mySQL
- Sequelize
- REACT

- MongoDB
- Node
- Express
- Adobe Lightroom
- Photoshop

WORK HISTORY

Nikki Dodge Photography - Wedding Photographer

OCTOBER 2016 - PRESENT

- Edited media on Adobe Lightroom and delivered finished product to client on strict deadlines.
- Utilize professional Canon DSLR cameras, studio lighting equipment, Adobe editing software and an understanding of aesthetic forms to design images.

The Marc, San Marcos, TX- Events & Concert Photographer

JANUARY 2018 - MARCH 2020

Photography work used for eventual promotion techniques and to continually update the company's social media.

Texas State Football - Photographer / Social Media Coordinator

2018 & 2019 SEASON

- Production of media for all football games and team related content for a Division I team.
- Develop, implement and monitor our content marketing strategy thereby working closely with other marketing and design departments